Professor Dave here, let's discuss the
zeroth law of thermodynamics.
Thermodynamics is a tricky subject that
must be studied in chemistry, physics,
engineering, and many other courses of
academic study, because it has an
incredible impact on the behavior of
matter and energy. At first, thermodynamic
concepts may seem impossible to
understand, but if you go over the basics
enough times they start to make sense
and you can continue to learn more about
the subject as needed for your field of
study or level of desired knowledge.
We will begin our analysis with the
infamous laws of thermodynamics. Just
like Newton's laws of motion there is a
first, second, and third law, but later in
the development of the field a more
fundamental law was added and dubbed the
zeroth law, so let's start there.
The zeroth law of thermodynamics deals with
thermal equilibrium, which as we recall
describes a situation in which there is
no net heat flow between two systems.
The zeroth law states that if two systems
are in thermal equilibrium with a third
system, then those two systems are also
in thermal equilibrium with each other.
In other words, if A is in thermal
equilibrium with B which is in thermal
equilibrium with C, A and C are also in
equilibrium. This may seem like a trivial
statement but it is an important one
because it means that two objects at the
same temperature will not exhibit heat
flow when they come into contact with
one another. This marks temperature as
the indicator of thermal equilibrium.
If two objects are in thermal equilibrium
with thermometers that read the same
temperature, the objects will be in
thermal equilibrium with each other
which therefore allows us to gather all
kinds of thermodynamic data in our
laboratories. In studying thermodynamics
we must also learn certain definitions.
We will want to be able to define a
system as the collection of objects we
are examining while the surroundings
represent the environment surrounding
the system, which is technically the rest
of the universe. Some systems allow heat
to flow in and out. These systems have
diathermal walls. Some systems do not
allow heat to flow in and out. These
systems have adiabatic walls. No system
can be truly adiabatic, but it is a
useful approximation when we do
calculations involving systems that
permit only negligible heat transfer.
With these definitions out of the way, we
can move on to the first law of thermodynamics.
Thanks for watching, guys. Subscribe to my channel for
more tutorials, support me on patreon so I can
keep making content, and as always feel
free to email me: